<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="xsl/main.xsl"?>
<page xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">

<h2>AP Computer Science Course Syllabus</h2>

<p><em>
The <strong>AP</strong> notation included in this course title indicates <strong>Advanced Placement</strong>. 
This course is similar to an introductory college course in computer science. Many career-disciplines; such 
as computer programming, mathematics, engineering, business, and the natural sciences; require fundamental 
computer programming skills. Students can gain college credit through this course. Students will learn to 
write object-oriented programs using the Java language to solve a variety of problems using common algorithms 
and data structures. The class will be conducted in a computer-lab setting. Additional laboratory time 
outside of class will be required. Students taking the <strong>AP</strong> version of the class will be prepared to take the 
College Board Advanced Placement exam in May and are expected to take the exam. 
</em></p>


<h3>Required Supplies</h3>
<ul class="supplies">
	<li>
		Textbook: <em>Java Software Solutions for AP* Computer Science. Authors: Lewis/ Loftus/Cocking</em>
	</li>
	<li>
		A spiral notebook for taking notes. 
	</li>
	<li>
		Pencil with eraser and pen. 
	</li>
	<li>
		A folder with pockets to hold handouts
	</li>
	<li>
		<em>(Optional) A home computer with <a href="http://eclipse. org">Eclipse IDE for Java Developers</a></em>. 
	</li>
</ul>


<h3>Assignments</h3>
<p>
Assignments will be given throughout the course. Some will be written assignments; most will be computer based 
assignments. Assignments will have a due date and will lose points if turned in late. Students are encouraged 
to work together on assignments as long as all students type their own work rather than copying work from 
other students. Work that has been copied electronically from another source will not receive credit and will 
not be eligible to be made up. Turning in electronic copies of work from another source will also be subject to 
further disciplinary action.
</p>

<h3>Quizzes and Tests</h3>
<p>
Quizzes and Tests will be given at key points throughout the course. Students are expected to take notes during 
lecture portions of the class. Quizzes and Tests will be based on information given during lectures and on 
knowledge gained from working on assignments. Students will be instructed exactly what should be put in the 
notes. Taking notes using paper and pencil is preferred as opposed to taking notes using the computer. There 
will be no surprise tests. If you are absent the day before the test/quiz, you will still be expected to take 
the test on the scheduled day. If you are absent on the day of a test, you must take the test on the day you return.
</p>

<h3>Absences</h3>
<p>
You are expected to be in class everyday. If you miss class, it is your responsibility to find out what you 
missed (copy notes from someone), and make arrangements for making up quizzes and tests promptly. You have one 
more day than the number of days absent to make up all missed work: assignments, quizzes, and tests. (Example: 
if you are absent three days, you have four days to make up all the work. Any work that is not turned in or 
taken in those four days will count as a zero.)
</p>

<h3>Tardies</h3>
<p>
You are expected to be in class at the scheduled time. Tardy is defined as not being in the classroom when the 
bell rings. All tardies will be handled as per the school's policy for tardies.
</p>

<h3>Grading</h3>
<p>
The weight of each assessment for the course is: assignments (40%) quizzes and tests (60%). It is important for 
students to understand the concepts and programming code done during assignments in order to perform well on the 
tests and quizzes. The course follows the standard grading scale:<br />
<strong>A: 90. 0%-100%, B: 80%-89. 9%, C: 70%-79. 9%, D: 60%-69. 9%, F: Below 60%</strong>.
</p>

<h3>Final Exam</h3>
<p>
There will be a final exam for semester 1 and for semester 2. Students enrolled in the AP course are exempt 
from the final exam for the second semester because the AP test taken in the spring serves as an assessment 
of student ability. The official semester grade will be calculated as 45% from each quarter in the semester 
(two quarters per semester), and 10% from the final exam. In the case of 2nd semester AP students, the final 
grade will be calculated as 50% from each quarter in the semester (there is no final exam for these students). 
</p>

<h3>Teacher Availability</h3>
<p>
I am available in room 304 (computer lab) at least 30 minutes before school. Students who need more 
individualized time are encouraged to make arrangements with me to meet at a mutually agreed upon time. 
</p>

<h3>Reporting of Academic Progress</h3>
<p>
Grades are available for viewing through Family Access on the Internet. Grades are updated weekly, usually 
over the weekend. If you cannot access your grade through family access, or have any questions about your 
grade, please contact me directly. 
</p>

<h3>Academic Honesty</h3>
<p>
The academic honesty policy as set forth by the school (on page 21 of the Student Planner and Handbook) will 
be used in this class. Specifically, immediate action will be taken for any student suspected of cheating on 
an assignment or test. 
</p>

</page>
