<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="xsl/main.xsl"?>
<page xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">

<h2>Advanced Topic in Computer Science</h2>
<p><em>
This course addresses topics in computer science that are beyond the scope of the AP and 
Honors computer science curricula. Topics include Event Driven programming, Graphical 
User Interface design and programming, Client/Server and Web programming, Database 
Connectivity, and Multi-Threaded programming. These topics will enable students to design 
and develop software solutions that are more comprehensive and realworld based compared to 
the AP and Honors courses. 
</em></p>

<h3>Assignments</h3>
<p>
Assignments will be given throughout the course. Most will be computer based assignments. 
Assignments will have a due date and will lose points if turned in late. Students are 
encouraged to work together on assignments as long as all students type their own work rather 
than copying work from other students. Work that has been copied electronically from another 
source will not receive credit and will not be eligible to be made up. Turning in electronic 
copies of work from another source will also be subject to further disciplinary action.
</p>

<h3>Absences</h3>
<p>
You are expected to be in class everyday. If you miss class, it is your responsibility to 
find out what you missed (copy notes from someone). You have one more day than the number 
of days absent to make up all missed work. (Example: if you are absent three days, you have 
four days to make up all the work. Any work that is not turned in or taken in those four days 
will count as a zero.)
</p>

<h3>Tardies</h3>
<p>
You are expected to be in class at the scheduled time. Tardy is defined as not being in the 
classroom when the bell rings. All tardies will be handled as per the school's policy for tardies. 
</p>

<h3>Grading</h3>
<p>
Assignments will have point values and will receive points based on the quality of work turned 
in. Students will have the opportunity to fix errors in assignments and resubmit them within a 
reasonable timeframe. The course follows the standard grading scale:<br />
<strong>A: 90.0%-100%, B: 80%-89.9%, C: 70%-79.9%, D: 60%-69.9%, F: Below 60%</strong>.
</p>

<h3>Final Exam</h3>
<p>
There will be a final exam in the form of a project. The official semester grade will be 
calculated as 45% from each quarter in the semester (two quarters per semester), and 10% 
from the final exam. 
</p>

<h3>Teacher Availability</h3>
<p>
I am available in room 304 (computer lab) at least 30 minutes before school. Students who need 
more individualized time are encouraged to make arrangements with me to meet at a mutually agreed 
upon time.
</p>

<h3>Reporting of Academic Progress</h3>
<p>
Grades are available for viewing through Family Access on the Internet. Grades are updated weekly, 
usually over the weekend. If you cannot access your grade through family access, or have any 
questions about your grade, please contact me directly.
</p>

<h3>Academic Honesty</h3>
<p>
The academic honesty policy as set forth by the school (on page 21 of the Student Planner and 
Handbook) will be used in this class. Specifically, immediate action will be taken for any student 
suspected of cheating on an assignment or test.
</p>

</page>
