<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="xsl/main.xsl"?>
<page xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">

<h2>Intro to Computer Science Course Syllabus</h2>
<p><em>
This course provides an introduction to computer science programming. Students will discover 
the theory and power of computers by learning to write computer programs to conduct 
experiments and solve practical problems. The course will focus on several programming 
languages to facilitate students' learning of computer programming solutions. Languages 
include Scratch, Python, and Java. The course prepares students for the more rigorous AP 
Computer Science or Honors Computer Science courses. Most of the work for the class will be 
done during class-time in a computer-lab setting under the supervision of the teacher. Some 
laboratory time outside of class may be required; a home computer with Internet access can 
serve this purpose. 
</em></p>

<h3>Required Supplies</h3>
<ul class="supplies">
	<li>
		Textbook: None, materials and notes will be supplied in class.
	</li>
	<li>
		A Notebook for taking notes.
	</li>
	<li>
		Something to write with, pencils with erasers are more helpful than pens.
	</li>
	<li>
		<em>(Optional) A home computer with <a href="http://scratch.mit.edu">Scratch</a>, 
		<a href="http://www.python.org">Python</a>, 
		<a href="http://www.oracle.com/technetwork/java/index.html">Java SE JDK</a>, 
		and <a href="http://www.eclipse.org">Eclipse IDE for Java Developers</a>. 
		All software tools used in class are available for free via Internet downloads.</em>
	</li>
</ul>

<h3>Assignments</h3>
<p>
Assignments will be given throughout the course. Some will be written assignments; most will be 
computer programming assignments. Assignments will have a due date and will lose points if 
turned in late. Students are encouraged to work together on assignments as long as all students
type their own work rather than copying work from other students. Work that has been copied 
electronically from another source will not receive credit and will not be eligible to be made 
up. Turning in electronic copies of work from another source will also be subject to further 
disciplinary action.
</p>

<h3>Quizzes and Tests</h3>
<p>
Quizzes and Tests will be given at key points throughout the course. Students are expected to 
take notes during lecture portions of the class. Quizzes and Tests will be based on information 
given during lectures and on knowledge gained from working on assignments. Students will be 
instructed exactly what should be put in the notes. Taking notes using paper and pencil is 
preferred as opposed to taking notes using the computer. There will be no surprise tests. 
If you are absent the day before the test/quiz, you will still be expected to take the test on 
the scheduled day. If you are absent only on the day of a test, you must take the test on the 
day you return. 
</p>

<h3>Absences</h3>
<p>
You are expected to be in class everyday. If you have any absences that you know about in advance,
please tell me beforehand. In any case, it is your responsibility to find out what you missed 
(copy notes from someone), and make arrangements for making up quizzes and tests promptly. You 
have one more day than the number of days absent to make up all missed work: assignments, quizzes, 
and tests. (Example: if you are absent three days, you have four days to make up all the work.
Any work that is not turned in or taken in those four days will count as a zero.) 
</p>

<h3>Tardies</h3>
<p>
You are expected to be in class at the scheduled time. Tardy is defined as not being in the 
classroom when the bell rings. All tardies will be handled as per the school's policy for tardies.
</p>

<h3>Grading</h3>
<p>
The weight of each assessment for the course is: assignments (50%) quizzes and tests (50%). It 
is important for students to understand the programming code in their assignments in order to 
perform well on the tests and quizzes. The course follows the standard grading scale:<br />
<strong>A: 90.0%-100%, B: 80%-89.9%, C: 70%-79.9%, D: 60%-69.9%, F: Below 60%</strong>.
</p>

<h3>Final Exam</h3>
<p>
There will be a final exam at the end of the semester. The exam will be based on the notes taken 
during the semester. The final semester grade will be composed of the regular course work 
(90%) and the final exam (10%)
</p>

<h3>Teacher Availability</h3>
<p>
I am available in room 304 (computer lab) 30 minutes before school. Students who need more 
individualized time are encouraged to make arrangements with me to meet at a mutually agreed upon time.
</p>

<h3>Reporting of Academic Progress</h3>
<p>
Grades are available for viewing through Family Access on the Internet. Grades are updated
weekly, usually over the weekend. If you cannot access your grade through family access, or
have any questions about your grade, please contact me directly.
</p>

<h3>Academic Honesty</h3>
<p>
The academic honesty policy as set forth by the school (on page 21 of the Student Planner
and Handbook) will be used in this class. Specifically, immediate action will be taken for
any student suspected of cheating on an assignment or test.
</p>

</page>