<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="xsl/main.xsl"?>
<page xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">

<h2>Plane Geometry Course Syllabus</h2>

<p><em>
This course involves exploration of inductive and deductive reasoning through the study of traditional 
relationships from Euclidian geometry including points, lines, planes, triangles, polygons, circles, 
areas, and volumes. Problem solving skills and proof writing are emphasized.
</em></p>

<h3>Required Supplies</h3>
<ul class="supplies">
	<li>
		Textbook: <em>McDougal Little Geometry - ISBN 978-0-618-59540-2</em>
	</li>
	<li>
		A spiral notebook for taking notes.
	</li>
	<li>
		Pencils with erasers.
	</li>
	<li>
		A folder with pockets to hold handouts
	</li>
</ul>

<h3>Assignments</h3>
<p>
Assignments will be given throughout the course. Assignments may be required to be completed during 
class time and/or as homework. Assignments will have a due date and will lose points if turned in 
late. Students are encouraged to work together on assignments as long as all students understand their 
work rather than copying work from other students. 
</p>

<h3>Quizzes and Tests</h3>
<p>
Quizzes and Tests will be given at key points throughout the course. Students are expected to take notes 
during lecture portions of the class. Quizzes and Tests will be based on information given during 
lectures and on knowledge gained from assignments. If you are only absent the day before the test/quiz, 
you will still take the test on the scheduled day. If you are absent only on the day of a test, you must 
take the test on the day you return. 
</p>

<h3>Absences</h3>
<p>
You are expected to be in class everyday. If you miss class, it is your responsibility to find out what 
you missed (copy notes from someone), and make arrangements for making up quizzes and tests promptly. 
You have one more day than the number of days absent to make up all missed work: assignments, quizzes, 
and tests. (Example: if you are absent three days, you have four days to make up all the work. Any work 
that is not turned in or taken in those four days will count as a zero.)  
</p>

<h3>Tardies</h3>
<p>
You are expected to be in class at the scheduled time. Tardy is defined as not being in the classroom 
when the bell rings. All tardies will be handled as per the school's policy for tardies. 
</p>

<h3>Grading</h3>
<p>
The weight of each assessment for the course is: preparation of assignments (35%) quizzes and tests 
(65%). There will be a final exam for each semester of the course. The official semester grade will 
be calculated from the 1st quarter grade (40%), the 2nd quarter grade (40%), and the final exam (20%).
At least two items per week will be given that receive a grade (assignments, tests, or quizzes). The 
course follows the standard grading scale: <br /><strong>A: 90.0%-100%, B: 80%-89.9%, C: 70%-79.9%, 
D: 60%-69.9%, F: Below 60%</strong>.
</p>

<h3>Teacher Availability</h3>
<p>
I am available in room 304 thirty minutes before school. Students who need more individualized time 
are encouraged to visit the tutoring center or make arrangements with me to meet at a mutually agreed 
upon time.
</p>

<h3>Reporting of Academic Progress</h3>
<p>
Grades for students are available via Family Access on the Internet. These grades will be updated on 
a weekly basis. Please contact me directly if you have questions about grades or if you have problems 
accessing them online.
</p>

<h3>Academic Honesty</h3>
<p>
The academic honesty policy as set forth by the school (on page 21 of the Student Planner and Handbook) 
will be used in this class. Specifically, immediate action will be taken for any student suspected of 
cheating on a quiz or test.
</p>

</page>
